careerfoundry.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy | CareerFoundry

At CareerFoundry GmbH, Marienburgerstrasse 10, 10405 Berlin, Germany (hereinafter referred to as “CareerFoundry” or “we/us”) we are fully aware of the importance of your privacy. We would, therefore, like to take this opportunity to give you a quick overview about our security measures and how we protect your personal data. 

This Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by CareerFoundry and our subsidiaries when you use our website www.careerfoundry.com (the “Website” or the "Service") or when you otherwise interact with us. You can find out more about us on www.careerfoundry.com. Regarding the Service, CareerFoundry complies with the applicable laws and regulations, in particular with the German Federal Data Protection Act and the German Telemedia Act. 

CareerFoundry has established a career accelerator for vocational tech skills. 

As you use our Service we want you to know how we collect, store and process your information. We created this Privacy Policy for you to get all the information you need to protect your privacy. We would like you to carefully read all the information we provide you and if there are any questions left, please do not hesitate to contact us at any time. 

Please direct all inquiries directly to: [hello@CareerFoundry.com](mailto:hello@CareerFoundry.com)

## 1\. What kind of information qualifies as Personal Data?

"Personal Data" shall mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('Data Subject'), e.g. your name, your address, your telephone number or your e-mail address. An identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. 

## 2\. What kind of data does CareerFoundry collect?

We collect data you directly provide us with when submitting any kind of information to us, e.g. when you sign up for an account. Even though you do not directly provide us with any Personal Data CareerFoundry may collects anonymous information about you, such as Google Analytics data. 

## 2.1 Information you submit to CareerFoundry

The use of our Website and Service requires you to create an account on www.careerfoundry.com. When you create an account we will ask you for your Personal Data, in particular for your name, postal address and email address.

## 2.2 Information CareerFoundry gets from your use of Service

As described in sec. 2 we may collect information concerning your usage behavior. We may collect different data in this regard. For example we may collect information about how you got to our Website and how you use our Service. This means we may take a look on operating systems you use our Service with. We also may aggregate which parts of our Service you use the most. 

## 3\. How will the information be used by CareerFoundry?

Unless you give us your separate and express consent to other uses of your Personal Data, we collect, store and process the Personal Data that you submit to us only to the extent required for you to use our Service, or to the extent that such use is allowed in accordance with other legal provisions, even without your consent, in particular for responding to your inquiries. 

The Personal Data you directly submit to us will only be used to identify you as a customer of our Service, to contact you if necessary and to issue invoices. We will store all Personal Data you submitted directly to CareerFoundry in our database. All Personal Data will be handled by CareerFoundry in strict confidence according to legal provisions such as the German Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz). 

Besides we only collect anonymous information about you to provide better service to all of our users. We will use the anonymous information to evaluate our Service activities and improve our Service. 

## 4\. Will CareerFoundry share your data?

CareerFoundry will only transfer or process personal data to third parties if this is required for statutory or legal reasons and/or if CareerFoundry has your explicit consent to do so.

CareerFoundry shall be entitled to collect, process and use your personal data for the purpose of identifying, delimiting and removing malfunctions and errors in the Service. If the requirements are met, CareerFoundry may collect, process and use personal data that is necessary to uncover any unlawful use of the Service. In accordance with prevailing legal provisions, CareerFoundry may provide information to criminal prosecution authorities and courts for prosecution purposes. 

## 5\. Google Analytics

The following web analytic service is used to improve the user experience of our Services:

We use Google Analytics, a service for the marketing analysis of this Website, of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses codes consisting of text and numbers, which will be stored on your computer and which allow for an analysis of the use of the Website ("Cookies"). The information generated by the Cookie about your use of the Website (including your IP address) will be transferred to and stored by a Google Server. Google will use this information, to evaluate your use of the Website, to prepare reports about the Website activities for the Website operators and to provide further services connected to the use of websites and the use of the Internet. Google may transfer this information to third parties, if legally obliged to do so or if third parties process these data on behalf of Google. In no case, Google will connect your IP address with other data from Google.

You can remove or deactivate such Cookies using the settings of your computer; in such a case you might not be able to fully use all functions of this Website. By using this Website you agree to the processing of your personal data by Google to the extent and purpose stated above. You can refuse to allow your data to be passed on by using a deactivation add-on for browsers under https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.

## 6\. Facebook Plugin

Our Website uses social plugins ("Plugins") of the social network facebook.com, which is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). You can view the list of Facebook social plugins and see what they look like here: <http://www.developers.facebook.com/plugins>

If you click on a page of our Website that contains this sort of Plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection with the Facebook servers. Facebook directly transfers the Plugin content to your browser which embeds the latter into the Website. We cannot influence the scope of data that Facebook collects with the help of this Plugin, meaning that the information we provide is based on our current knowledge.

The embedding of the Plugin informs Facebook that you accessed the respective page of our Website. If you are logged into Facebook, Facebook can assign the visit to your Facebook account. If you interact with the Plugins, e.g. by clicking on the "Register with Facebook" button, the corresponding information is transmitted from your browser directly to Facebook, where it will be saved. If you are not a member of Facebook, it is still possible for Facebook to identify and save your IP address. For information on the purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and utilisation of the data by Facebook, as well as your rights in this respect and the settings that you can adjust to protect your privacy, please consult Facebook's data protection information: http://www.facebook.com/policy.php. 

If you are a member of Facebook and want to prevent Facebook from collecting data on you via our Website and linking this data to your member data stored with Facebook, you may not register with Facebook and log out of Facebook before you visit our Website. You will be able to connect our Service with Facebook via the Facebook “Register with Facebook” button on our Website. If you do so your email-address and your Facebook User-ID will be transferred to and stored by CareerFoundry. The Facebook privacy rules apply to the usage of the “Register with Facebook” button. If you do not want your data transferred in the aforementioned way, please refrain from using the “Register with Facebook” button. 

## 7\. Cookies

CareerFoundry makes use of cookies to store session information, to help you sign up for our Services, to protect your data and to provide users with a customized Service through identifying unique visitors and their respective usage patterns. Cookies are identifiers (miniature text files) that can be saved temporarily or permanently on a User’s hard drive by the server. Cookies guarantee the consistency of each communication process. Temporary cookies can be used to identify which visits are all part of a single session. Permanent cookies are for pre-recognizing a user, for instance so that individual settings can be made. Users are free to decide whether to let their browser use cookies. All browser programs allow cookies to be deactivated or deleted. When we use cookies no personally identifiable information will be collected. 

All information, whether on data processors on CareerFoundry’s premises or on servers acting on CareerFoundry’s behalf, remains in complete control of CareerFoundry at all times. 

## 8\. Stripe

If you choose to use our Service we will process payments through our third party credit card processor. All such transactions will be governed by the Stripe privacy policy at stripe.com/privacy. We do not receive or store credit card information into our servers. We receive a transaction “token” and a one-time use ID number so we can validate that the transaction has been successfully completed. Because we do not retain your credit card information, you will need to re-enter your information each time you make a payment. 

## 9\. Keep your personal information up to date

You will be able to update your account information that you submitted to CareerFoundry at any time. We would like you to change or delete your information in case it is wrong.

## 10\. Newsletter

You will be able to subscribe to our newsletter on our Website. After you subscribe, CareerFoundry will send you an email to confirm your subscription. Until you unsubscribe to our newsletter, we will use your email address for our own promotion purposes, e.g. providing content related to freelance, ux and web development, if you have given your consent to it. You may cancel your subscription at any time and free of charge by using the link in the newsletter or sending us a notification to: [hello@CareerFoundry.com](mailto:hello@CareerFoundry.com). 

## 11\. Security

We employ technical and organizational measures including two-step verification process, password and physical security measures in order to safeguard the Service against loss, theft, misuse, destruction, access, alteration or the disclosure of your data by unauthorized persons. Despite regular controls a complete protection against all dangers is, however, not possible. The access to your account is possible only after entering your personal password. You should always treat your access information confidentially and close the browser window, once you have ended your communication with us, particularly if you share the use of the computer with others. CareerFoundry can not warrant security for data transmitted to our Service because unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. CareerFoundry is based in Germany. The information we collect is governed by the applicable German law and European directives. If you have any queries about the security of our Service, please do not hesitate to contact us at any time on [hello@CareerFoundry.com](mailto:hello@CareerFoundry.com). 

## 12\. Your rights

The Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz) guarantees you rights to information, correction, deletion or blocking of your personal data. Upon request, we shall provide you with the information on the stored data relating to your person, free of charge and without delay. The information can be provided electronically, if desired. In cases regulated by law we are obliged, upon request, to correct, block or delete the data stored about you. Please direct all requests directly to: [hello@CareerFoundry.com](mailto:hello@CareerFoundry.com)

## 13\. Changes

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the bottom of the policy and, if the changes are significant, we will provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our Website). To better protect your privacy you may review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Service to stay informed about our information practices. 

## 14\. Contact

For further information, please contact [hello@CareerFoundry.com](mailto:hello@CareerFoundry.com) or write us at: CareerFoundry GmbH, Marienburgerstr. 10, 10405 Berlin, Germany. 

Last Updated: June 18, 2014
